<?xml version="1.0"?>  <!DOCTYPE rss PUBLIC "-//Netscape Communications//DTD RSS 0.91//EN" "">

<rss version="0.94">

    <channel>
        <title>MapDB - News</title>
        <link>http://www.mapdb.org/</link>
        <description>MapDB </description>

        <item>
            <title>MapDB 1.0 will be released in January</title>
            <link>http://kotek.net/blog/MapDB_1_in_january</link>
            <date>November 6 2013</date>
            <description>
                I am happy to announce that everything is on track for MapDB 1.0 to be released on January 2014.
            </description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>MapDB 0.9.7 released</title>
            <link>http://www.mapdb.org/changelog.html#/Version_097_2013-10-28</link>
            <date>October 28 2013</date>
            <description>
                MapDB 0.9.7 was just released. Fixed locking issues on Windows. Concurrent Transactions (TxMaker) reworked and finally fixed.
            </description>
        </item>


        <item>
            <title>MapDB 0.9.6 released</title>
            <link>http://www.mapdb.org/changelog.html#/Version_096_2013-09-27</link>
            <date>September 27 2013</date>
            <description>
                MapDB 0.9.6 was just released. Concurrent Transactions (TxMaker) almost fixed. Backward incompatible store format change.
                Snapshots are no longer enabled by default.
            </description>
        </item>


        <item>
            <title>MapDB and the road ahead</title>
            <link>http://kotek.net/blog/MapDB_and_the_road_ahead</link>
            <date>September 25 2013</date>
            <description>
                Post about MapDB future.
            </description>
        </item>


        <item>
            <title>MapDB 0.9.5 released</title>
            <link>http://www.mapdb.org/changelog.html#/Version_095_2013-08-26</link>
            <date>August 26 2013</date>
            <description>
                MapDB 0.9.5 was just released.  Fixed some data corruption issues. CRC32 replaced by faster Adler32. I will be offline until 4th Sept.
            </description>
        </item>


        <item>
            <title>MapDB 0.9.4 released</title>
            <link>http://www.mapdb.org/changelog.html#/Version_094_2013-08-09</link>
            <date>August 09 2013</date>
            <description>
                MapDB 0.9.4 was just released. It is not backward compatible with previous releases. Many improvements.
            </description>
        </item>


        <item>
            <title>MapDB 0.9 format support</title>
            <link>http://kotek.net/blog/MapDB_09_format_support</link>
            <date>July 01 2013</date>
            <description>
                MapDB has currently semi-stable branch 0.9.x. My plan was to keep stable API and storage format. However
                to support some new features (store size limit, async API) I have to make changes in storage format,
                which are not backward compatible. Also now I work full-time and project is evolving much faster than I
                expected.
            </description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>MapDB Reloaded</title>
            <link>http://kotek.net/blog/MapDB_Reloaded</link>
            <date>June 19 2013</date>
            <description>
                Last month I wrote about<a href="http://kotek.net/blog/MapDB_Future">the future of MapDB</a>. It was not
                very optimistic. MapDB is my hobby project and the time I could give it is severely limited. This led to
                some absurd situations: despite having a very fast db-engine I would not publish any performance
                benchmarks. I also discouraged possible users so I would not have to deal with support emails.
            </description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>MapDB Future</title>
            <link>http://kotek.net/blog/MapDB_Future</link>
            <date>April 23 2013</date>
            <description>
                MapDB 0.9.x was released a few weeks ago. Now that the project enters<i>usable alpha phase</i>, is time
                to talk about the future.
            </description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>3 billion items in Java Map with 16 GB RAM</title>
            <link>http://kotek.net/blog/3G_map</link>
            <date>November 12 2012</date>
            <description>
                One rainy evening I meditated about memory management in Java and
                how effectively Java collections utilise memory.
                I made simple experiment, how much entries can I insert into
                Java Map with 16 GB of RAM?
            </description>
        </item>

        <item>
            <title>JDBM4 renamed to MapDB</title>
            <link>http://kotek.net/blog/JDBM4_renamed_to_MapDB</link>
            <date>November 03 2012</date>
            <description>
                'JDBM' (Java Database Manager) name has long history. Original 'DBM' (Database Manager) has been
                introduced in seventies. Java version started in 2001 and first stable version was introduced in 2005.
                Until 2012 it has dozen forks including JDBM2,3,4 and ApacheDS.
            </description>
        </item>

    </channel>
</rss>